

# Contacts



+46705 - 71 70 38



🔀 rasmus@rctl.io



in linkedin.com/in/rasmusjoensson



🐪 rctl.io



github.com/rctl



twitter.com/\_rctl

# Experience

Nov 2017-

# **Product Manager**

Building the development team at Worldish AB where we create software to eliminate language barriers in healthcare. Our core is built in Go, Kotlin and Vue.

Worldish AB

Feb 2017-Apr 2018

## **Lead Developer**

Leading the development in creating an application built in C# .NET for customer. Was involved in the start-up process working with customer relations and sales as a technical advisor.

Unitalent AB

Jun 2017-Aug 2017

### **Software Engineering Intern**

Working as a technical intern at Opera during the summer of 2017 developing productivity tools for the Opera Mini team. Worked with Python, Automated testing, Data analysis and monitoring

Opera Software

Apr 2016-Aug 2016

### **Software Developer Intern**

Lead developer on app backed built with Go running on Google App Engine. Consultant working with a webshop built with PHP during summer.

Jun 2015-Aug 2015

## **Software Developer Intern**

Consultant working with large-scale web application built in C#.NET.

**XLENT AB** 

2014-

#### Consultant

Self-employed consultant working with many projects. Running Kubernetes clusters and managing services for some customers.

# About me

Very interested in technology and large-scale web systems. Interested in leadership and have experience in leading groups of people. Working fluently with Go, Python, JS, Java, Kotlin, C#, Docker, Kubernetes, nginx and Linux. Knowledge in HTTP, TCP/IP, TLS, DNS, Load balancing, Virtual machines etc. Been volunteering at festival NärCon since 2012 which draws over 15 000 visitors, my responsibilities was to manage the infrastructure team of about 6 people and planning networks and electricity supply to the event. Chairman for Team Obelix at Linköping University, we organize visits to companies for other students. Born in 1994, fluent in english and has swedish drivers license.

# Education

# **2017-** Master of Science in Information Technology

Continued studies at Linköping University. Doing master courses in A.I., leadership, web programming and patent-law. I'm also working part-time.

Linköping University

# **2014-** Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Studying at Linköping University. Still finishing this degree while I also study master courses and work part-time. At university I have been able to branch more into advanced technology through my studies. With a particular interest for computational efficiency and optimisation.

Linköping University

## 2013-2014 Information and Media Technology

Continued studies due to JB Gymnasiet being canceled. At NTI I developed a project that allowed all students to get free web-hosting. I also wrote a paper about this work. Students could sign up with their student email in a web-portal I developed and get instant access to hosting.

NTI Gymnasiet, Lund

# 2011-2013 Information and Media Technology

Studies in technology, math an physics at Swedish Gymnasium. I took two extra courses in programming; Programming level 2 and XNA Programming. At JB Gymnasiet we also worked with a lot of projects in technology such as game and android development

JB Gymnasiet, Hässleholm

# 2002-2011 Swedish elementary school

# Notable projects

#### 2017 Kubefront

Open-sourced dashboard for Kubernetes. Written in Vue and Go.

Source available on my GitHub profile.

#### 2017 kube-ci

kube-ci is an automated continuous delivery system for Kubernetes that directly integrates with Google Cloud Builder. kube-ci automatically detects successful builds and deploys new images to Kubernetes deployments seemlessly.

Source available on my GitHub profile.

### 2017 CryptoVoice

CryptoVoice is a free VOIP application for Android that I have developed. It features secure end-to-end AES encryption. It also features a security feature using RSA that enhances authenticity for CryptoVoice numbers used in dialing. Due to lack of time to do maintenance this has been unpublished from Google Play.

Source available on my GitHub profile.

### 2015 PGP ID

PGP ID is an android application enabling two-factor authentication using PGP certificate to verify identity. Similar to swedish BankID used by swedish banks. User signs in on an online service and verifies his/her identity with a PGP signature. Due to lack of time to do maintenance this has been unpublished from Google Play.

Source available on my GitHub profile.